Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection
1965 - 2000
NPKMC-222-159
78 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc.
The Hudson River Sloop Clearwater Collection consists of studies, reports, correspondence, and clippings documenting the society’s interests in local environmental issues. The collection also includes office materials, litigation, and Clearwater events.
Related Collections
Alexander Saunders Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962 - 1966
Hudson River Environmental Society Collection, 1963 - 2005
Hudson River Environmental Society Library, 1965 - 2001
Hudson River Valley Commission Collection: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1966 – 1967
Hudson River Valley Commission Collection: Records Relating to the 1965 – 1970 Surveys, 1955 – 1976
Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection, 1989 - 1996
Hudson Valley GREEN Collection, 1981 - 2002
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Dain Papers, 1963 - 1967
On the River Collection, 1986 - 1993
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Administrative History Collection, 1960 - 2000
Scenic Hudson Collection: Records relating to the Storm King Case, 1963 - 1981
Senator Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962 - 1978
Collection Overview
The Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection consists of correspondence, research materials, publications, memorandums, and legal documents pertaining to Clearwater’s participation in local environmental issues. Also included are materials used for researching purposes, including pamphlets, regulations, and manuals. Finally, the collection contains clippings and photographs of the environmental action and Clearwater events.
The Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection was given to the Marist College Library by the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc.
Historical Note
The Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. is a non-profit organization founded in 1966 dedicated to the education and preservation of the Hudson River. Its goal is “to defend and restore the Hudson River.” To achieve this goal, the Sloop Clearwater investigates and conducts research into any causes or sources of contamination of the river, informs the public of such dangers, and educates the public of the Hudson – its history, environment, as well as its dangers and ways to protect it. Since its founding, Sloop Clearwater has had many notable achievements. Among these are the building and launching of the Sloop – the first wooden sailing ship with a mission to preserve and protect the environment – playing a key role in the Clear Water Act and being the first to begin the 25-year battle with GE concerning PCBs in the Hudson. In addition to their research and activist, the Sloop Clearwater invites hundreds of kids each year from local schools to take a ride down the Hudson and learn first hand about the ecosystems and pollution. Clearwater has inspired many to protect and preserve the great waterways and will continue to do so for many years to come.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into seven series: 1. Environmental Action, has 37 subseries, 2. Publications, has 8 subseries, 3. Office papers, has 6 subseries, 4. John Mylod's Projects and Interests, 5. Clippings, 6. Photographs, and 7. Clearwaters Founding Materials, has 3 subseries.
- 1. Environmental Action, 1; 37.5 Linear Feet Boxes: 1 - 41 Folders: 1 - 1126
  This series contains a collection of materials pertaining to Clearwater’s participation and interests in local environmental concerns
  By subject
  - Subseries 1.1: Recycling, 1.1; Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 43
    Series contains Clearwater’s interest and action in recycling along the Hudson River.
    Alphabetical
    - Albany County (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - ANJEC Report, Fall 1986 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - Application Procedures for Source Separation/Recycling Resource Recovery Projects (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - Backup Landfill, Ask Disposal Site Screening Process - Position Statement, Oct. 1, 1986 (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - Beacon Proposed Recycling Law, Sept. 1990 (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - Bibliography of Recycling (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - Columbia County (Folder 7, Box 1)
    - Coming Full Circle: Successful Recycling Today (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Comprehensive Recycling Proposal (Folder 9, Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Folder 10, Box 1)
    - Display Ideas and Sketches (Folder 11, Box 1)
    - Dutchess County (Folder 12, Box 1)
    - Dutchess County Recycling Song (Folder 13, Box 1)
    - EMC Roundtable II - Solid Waste and Landfill Sitting Issues (Folder 14, Box 1)
    - Funding (Folder 15, Box 1)
    - A Garbage Recycling Program for New York City, Oct. 12, 1984 (Folder 16, Box 1)
    - Greene County (Folder 17, Box 1)
    - A Guide for Marketing Recyclable Materials (Folder 18, Box 1)
    - Hudson Valley Recycling Centers (Folder 19, Box 1)
    - New York Environmental News, April 30, 1986 (Folder 20, Box 1)
    - New York State (Folder 21, Box 1)
    - Orange County (Folder 22, Box 1)
    - Organization and Delegation Memorandum - Source Separating/Recycling, Sept. 3, 1986 (Folder 23, Box 1)
    - Part 368 (Recycling Emblems) (Folder 24, Box 1)
    - Publications and Clippings (Folder 25, Box 1)
    - Purchase of Recycled Paper Products (Folder 26, Box 1)
    - Putnam County (Folder 27, Box 1)
    - PVC Packaging Correspondence (Folder 28, Box 1)
    - PVC Packaging Research Materials (Folder 29, Box 1)
    - PVC Packaging Ruling 1985-1986 (Folder 30, Box 1)
    - Recycling Act Chapter 24, Assembly No. 2283 (Folder 31, Box 1)
    - Recycling Legislation for New York State - Some Ideas and Directions (Folder 32, Box 1)
    - Recycling Markets (Folder 33, Box 1)
    - Rensselaer County (Folder 34, Box 1)
    - Rockland County (Folder 35, Box 1)
    - Source Separation Projects Utilizing EQBA Funds in New York State (Folder 36, Box 1)
    - Statement of Dutchess County Land Conservancy... Concerning Potential County Landfill Sites (Folder 37, Box 1)
    - Statement on Recycling, Nov. 26, 1986 (Folder 38, Box 1)
    - Sullivan County (Folder 39, Box 1)
    - Town of Islip Recycling Ordinance (Folder 40, Box 1)
    - Urban (Folder 41, Box 1)
    - Westchester County (Folder 42, Box 1)
    - Wrapped in Plastics (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Garbage Burning, 1.2; Box: 1 Folders: 44 - 63
    Series contains Clearwater’s interest and action in the prevention of garbage burning
    - An Act... Prohibiting... the Burning of Wastes when it would Result in [Unhealthy] Airborn Emissions... (Folder 44, Box 1)
    - The Burning Question: Garbage Incineration vs. Total Recycling in New York City - Summary (Folder 45, Box 1)
    - A Citizen Organizing Guide to Anti-Incineration Pro-Recycling Campaigns (Folder 46, Box 1)
    - Clippings (Folder 47, Box 1)
    - Composting (Folder 48, Box 1)
    - Evaluation of Potential Health Risks from Dioxin Contaminated Solids (Folder 49, Box 1)
    - The Financial and Environmental Impact of Garbage Incineration (Folder 50, Box 1)
    - Fliers (Folder 51, Box 1)
    - Malcolm Pirnie Update, April 1987 (Folder 52, Box 1)
    - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation: Air Emissions from Incinerator Facilities (Folder 53, Box 1)
    - New York State Incinerators (Folder 54, Box 1)
    - Petition (Folder 55, Box 1)
    - Playing With Fire: Hazardous Waste Incineration (Folder 56, Box 1)
    - Resource Recovery and Solid Waste Management Report (Folder 57, Box 1)
    - Revised 6 NYCRR Part 219 Incinerators Draft EIS (Folder 58, Box 1)
    - The Rush to Burn (Folder 59, Box 1)
    - Scrap Info Winter 1986 (Folder 60, Box 1)
    - Solid Waste Management in Japan Lessons for New York (Folder 61, Box 1)
    - Statement for Public Hearing (Folder 62, Box 1)
    - Times Union, Oct. 5-17, 1986 (Folder 63, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.3: SNARL Drinking Water, 1979 - 1982; 1.3; Box: 1 Folders: 64 - 87
    Series contains a collection of pamphlets from SNARL concerning contaminants in the drinking water
    Chronological
    - Disclaimer (Folder 64, Box 1)
    - Nov. 26, 1979: Tirichloroethylene (Folder 65, Box 1)
    - Feb. 6, 1980: Tetrachloroethylene (Folder 66, Box 1)
    - Feb. 16, 1980: Carbofuran (Folder 67, Box 1)
    - Mar. 10, 1980: Tetracholrethylene (Folder 68, Box 1)
    - March 19, 1980: Fuel Oil #2 or Kerosene (Folder 69, Box 1)
    - May 9, 1980: 1, 1, 1-Trichloroethane (Folder 70, Box 1)
    - March 14, 1981: Dichloromethane (Methylene Chloride) (Folder 71, Box 1)
    - June 23, 1981: Chlordane (Folder 72, Box 1)
    - Aug. 27, 1981: Formaldehyde (Folder 73, Box 1)
    - Sept. 11, 1981: Carbon Tetrachloride (Folder 74, Box 1)
    - Sept. 15, 1981: 1, 2-Dichloroethane (Folder 75, Box 1)
    - Sept. 21, 1981: 1, 2-Dichloroethylene (Folder 76, Box 1)
    - Sept. 22, 1981: 2-Dichloroethylene (Folder 77, Box 1)
    - Oct. 7, 1981: 1, 1-Dichloroethylene (Vinylidene Chloride) (Folder 78, Box 1)
    - Oct. 13, 1981: Xylenes (Dimethylbenzenes) (Folder 79, Box 1)
    - Nov. 19, 1981: Methyl Ethyl Ketone (Folder 80, Box 1)
    - Dec. 15, 1981: n-Hexane (Folder 81, Box 1)
    - March 23, 1982: Toluene (Folder 82, Box 1)
    - June 15, 1982: 1, 1-Dichloroethylene (Folder 83, Box 1)
    - Benzene (Folder 84, Box 1)
    - Uranium (Folder 85, Box 1)
    - March 19- Dichoromethane (Methylene Chloride) (Folder 86, Box 1)
    - Ethylene Glycol (Ethane - 1, 2-diol) (Folder 87, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.4: NIOSH, 1.4; Box: 2 Folders: 88 - 99
    Series contains a collection of publication from NIOSH concerning exposure to various contaminants
    - Current Intelligence Bulletin 1981-1985 (Folder 88, Box 2)
    - Hazard Alert (Folder 89, Box 2)
    - Health Hazard Evaluation Summaries, Jan. 1982 (Folder 90, Box 2)
    - Health Hazard Evaluation Summaries, May 1982 (Folder 91, Box 2)
    - New Publications (Folder 92, Box 2)
    - The Occupational Health and Safety Act (Folder 93, Box 2)
    - Occupational Health Guidelines for Chemical Hazards (Folder 94, Box 2)
    - Occupational Health Guidelines for Chemical Hazards cont’d (Folder 95, Box 2)
    - Occupational Health Guidelines for Chemical Hazards cont’d (Folder 96, Box 2)
    - Recommended Standard for Occupational Exposure to: A-D (Folder 97, Box 2)
    - Recommended Standard for Occupational Exposure to: E-K (Folder 98, Box 2)
    - Recommended Standard for Occupational Exposure to: L-Z (Folder 99, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.5: Angler Survey, 1.5; Box: 2 Folders: 100 - 124
    Series contains documents related to Clearwater's survey of Hudson River Angler questioning thier knowledge of PCBs
    - Angler Logs (Folder 100, Box 2)
    - Bibliography (Folder 101, Box 2)
    - Budget Notes (Folder 102, Box 2)
    - Clearwater Graphs (Folder 103, Box 2)
    - Clippings (Folder 104, Box 2)
    - Conclusions and Recommendations (Folder 105, Box 2)
    - Consultant for Angler Survey Project (Folder 106, Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Folder 107, Box 2)
    - Data Analysis, Oct. 1992 (Folder 108, Box 2)
    - Data Analysis, Nov. 24, 1992 (Folder 109, Box 2)
    - Data Analysis, Dec. 11, 1992 (Folder 110, Box 2)
    - Demographics (Folder 111, Box 2)
    - Estuary (Folder 112, Box 2)
    - Executive Summary, March 1993 (Folder 113, Box 2)
    - Fish Consumption (Folder 114, Box 2)
    - Health Advisories, Awareness, Attitude, Effectiveness (Folder 115, Box 2)
    - Health Advisories on Fish Consumption, 1992 Clearwater (Folder 116, Box 2)
    - Notes (Folder 117, Box 2)
    - Perception, Influence on Consumption, Other Factors (Folder 118, Box 2)
    - Proposal (Folder 119, Box 2)
    - Proposal Approval (Folder 120, Box 2)
    - Questionnaire (Folder 121, Box 2)
    - A Report on the Adherence to Fish Consumption Health Advisories among Hudson River Anglers (Folder 122, Box 2)
    - Reports (Folder 123, Box 2)
    - Transparencies (Folder 124, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.6: Westway, 1.6; Boxes: 2 - 5 Folders: 125 - 230
    Series contains documents, correspondence, and legal materials concerning the Westway reconstruction and payback
    - 1983 Correspondence (Folder 125, Box 2)
    - 1989-1990 Correspondence (Folder 126, Box 2)
    - 1990 Correspondence (Folder 127, Box 2)
    - 1990-1991 Correspondence (Folder 128, Box 2)
    - March 1991 Correspondence and Clippings (Folder 129, Box 2)
    - 1992 Correspondence (Folder 130, Box 2)
    - 1993-1994 Correspondence (Folder 131, Box 2)
    - 1991-1992 Memorandum of Understanding, etc. (Folder 132, Box 2)
    - 1991-1992 Waiver Amendment (Folder 133, Box 2)
    - Action Requests (Folder 134, Box 2)
    - Affidavits (Folder 135, Box 2)
    - Affidavit of Barbara Fife (Folder 136, Box 3)
    - Affidavit of Marcy Benstock (Folder 137, Box 3)
    - Amended Verified Petition under Article 78 (Folder 138, Box 3)
    - Army Corps/Dovel (Folder 139, Box 3)
    - ASMFC Habitat - Piers/Platforms (Folder 140, Box 3)
    - Battery Park City (Folder 141, Box 3)
    - City Club Luncheon - West Side Waterfront Park Remarks by Gene Russianoff (Folder 142, Box 3)
    - Clearwater Navigator July/Aug. 1992 - “Weaving Westway’s Tangled Web” (Folder 143, Box 3)
    - Clearwater Navigator Nov./Dec. 1992 - “Westway II Saga to Unfold in Court” (Folder 144, Box 3)
    - Clearwater Statement for Lawyers, July 6, 1992 (Folder 145, Box 3)
    - Clippings (Folder 146, Box 3)
    - Clippings cont’d (Folder 147, Box 3)
    - Clippings cont’d (Folder 148, Box 3)
    - Comments on Task Force (Folder 149, Box 3)
    - Complaint Drafts 1992 (Folder 150, Box 3)
    - Correspondence (misc.) (Folder 151, Box 3)
    - Deposition of Michael B. Gerrard (Folder 152, Box 3)
    - Deposition of Tom Fox (Folder 153, Box 3)
    - Depositions (Folder 154, Box 3)
    - Draft Application for a Westway Right-of-Way Payback Waiver (Folder 155, Box 3)
    - Draft Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement Lobbying Correspondence (Folder 156, Box 3)
    - Draft Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement: Vol I-Non-Fisheries Portion (Folder 157, Box 3)
    - Draft Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement: Vol II-Fisheries Portion (Folder 158, Box 3)
    - Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement: Vol I-Non-fisheries Portion (Folder 159, Box 3)
    - Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement: Vol II-Fisheries Portion (Folder 160, Box 3)
    - Fish and Wildlife (Folder 161, Box 3)
    - Fish Interest Lobbying (Folder 162, Box 3)
    - Follow the Money for Westway II (Folder 163, Box 3)
    - Greenwich Village Green Proposal (Folder 164, Box 3)
    - Holland Tunnel, Pier 34, Nov. 1993 (Folder 165, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Development Proposal (Folder 166, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Habitat Protection Act (Folder 167, Box 3)
    - HRPC Bidders Meeting, March 1993 (Folder 168, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Park Conservancy, Inc. (Folder 169, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Park Conversancy - “A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park” (Folder 170, Box 3)
    - Hudson River UDC Subsidiary Proposal - Preliminary Inventory of Problems (Folder 171, Box 3)
    - Issues 1995 History (Folder 172, Box 3)
    - Legal Correspondence (Folder 173, Box 3)
    - Limitation on Power of Public Authorities and Other Entities (Folder 174, Box 3)
    - M.O.U. at a Glance (Folder 175, Box 3)
    - Memorandum in Support of Motion to Disqualify, Nov. 2, 1992 (Folder 176, Box 3)
    - Memorandum in Support of Motion to Disqualify, Nov. 9, 1992 (Folder 177, Box 4)
    - Memorandum in Support of Motion to Disqualify, Dec. 7, 1992 (Folder 178, Box 4)
    - Memorandum of Opposition (Folder 179, Box 4)
    - Memorandum of Understanding (Folder 180, Box 4)
    - Memorandums to Marcy Benstock from Rob Lacy (Folder 181, Box 4)
    - Moratorium on West Side Development (Folder 182, Box 4)
    - Motion for Leave to Appear as Amici Curiae (Folder 183, Box 4)
    - Motion of Petitioners (Folder 184, Box 4)
    - Municipal Art Society West Side Design Contest (Folder 185, Box 4)
    - Neighborhood Open Space Coalition (Folder 186, Box 4)
    - New York City Clean Air Campaign (Folder 187, Box 4)
    - New York City Clean Air Campaign Correspondence (Folder 188, Box 4)
    - News Releases (Folder 189, Box 4)
    - Notes (Folder 190, Box 4)
    - Notice of Petition (Folder 191, Box 4)
    - Order to Show Cause (Folder 192, Box 4)
    - Paget/Task Force Memorandum (Folder 193, Box 4)
    - Paul Weiss Memorandum (Folder 194, Box 4)
    - Payback (Folder 195, Box 4)
    - Payback Dec. 1990 (Folder 196, Box 4)
    - Payback 1992 (Folder 197, Box 4)
    - Payback Waiver Application (Folder 198, Box 4)
    - Payback Waiver Oct. 1991 (Folder 199, Box 4)
    - Payback Waiver 1993 (Folder 200, Box 4)
    - Payback Waiver 1994 (Folder 201, Box 4)
    - Petition (Folder 202, Box 4)
    - Petitioners’ Memorandum of Law in Support of Motion to Sever (Folder 203, Box 4)
    - Petitioners’ Notice of Motion to Disqualify (Folder 204, Box 4)
    - Piers (Folder 205, Box 4)
    - Press on West Side Task Force (Folder 206, Box 4)
    - Press Release (Folder 207, Box 4)
    - Public Notice (Folder 208, Box 4)
    - Reply Memorandum in Support of Motion to Disqualify (Folder 209, Box 4)
    - Requests (Folder 210, Box 4)
    - Respondents’ Joint Memorandum of Law in Opposition to the Amended Verified Petition (Folder 211, Box 4)
    - Right-of-Way (Folder 212, Box 4)
    - Study of Sampling Requirements for the Westway Interpier Area Hudson River Estuary (Folder 213, Box 4)
    - Supplemental Memorandum of Respondents... in Opposition to Motion to Disqualify Council (Folder 214, Box 4)
    - Verified Answers (Folder 215, Box 4)
    - Verified Petition under Article 78 (Folder 216, Box 4)
    - “A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park” Draft Report Sept. 17, 1990 and Notes (Folder 217, Box 4)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park, 1990 (Folder 218, Box 4)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park - Recommendations Report, Sept. 17, 1990 (Folder 219, Box 4)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park - Recommendations Report, Nov 1, 1990 (Folder 220, Box 4)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park Report Appendix Vol. I (Folder 221, Box 5)
    - A Vision for the Hudson River Waterfront Park Report Appendix Vol. II (Folder 222, Box 5)
    - West Side Task Force (Folder 223, Box 5)
    - West Side Task Force Final Report 1/1987 (Folder 224, Box 5)
    - West Side Task Force Preliminary Report (Folder 225, Box 5)
    - West Side Waterfront Panel, 1990 (Folder 226, Box 5)
    - West Way Waterfront Panel Work Plan, 1989-1990 (Folder 227, Box 5)
    - Westway (1) (Folder 228, Box 5)
    - Westway (2) (Folder 229, Box 5)
    - Westway II (Folder 230, Box 5)
  - Subseries 1.7: Local Waterfront Revitalization Program (LWRP), 1.7; Boxes: 5 - 7 Folders: 231 - 264
    Series contains plans and information for the LWRP, mostly Poughkeepsie, NY
    - City of Poughkeepsie Draft Local Waterfront Revitalization Program '89 (Folder 231, Box 5)
    - City of Poughkeepsie Local Waterfront Revitalization Program ‘97 (Folder 232, Box 5)
    - City of Poughkeepsie Local Waterfront Revitalization Program ’86 (Folder 233, Box 5)
    - City of Poughkeepsie Local Waterfront Revitalization Program ’86 cont’d (Folder 234, Box 5)
    - County Waterfront Rezoning (Folder 235, Box 5)
    - Hudson River Significant Tidal Habitats (Folder 236, Box 5)
    - Hudson River Waterfront Advisory Committee (Folder 237, Box 5)
    - Kingston Waterfront (Folder 238, Box 5)
    - Local Waterfront Revitalization Program (Folder 239, Box 5)
    - LWRP Amendments to the Aug. 1989 Draft (Folder 240, Box 5)
    - LWRP Correspondence (Folder 241, Box 5)
    - LWRP Development and Design (Folder 242, Box 6)
    - LWRP Environmental Impact Statement (Folder 243, Box 6)
    - LWRP Executive Summary (Folder 244, Box 6)
    - LWRP Findings Statement (Folder 245, Box 6)
    - LWRP General Provisions (Folder 246, Box 6)
    - LWRP Hudson Valley Programs (Folder 247, Box 6)
    - LWRP Maps (Folder 248, Box 6)
    - LWRP Proposal (Folder 249, Box 6)
    - LWRP Report May 17, 1983 (Folder 250, Box 6)
    - Peekskill LWRP (Folder 251, Box 6)
    - Peekskill Redevelopment Plan Draft EIS (no folder) (Folder 252, Box 6)
    - Peekskill Redevelopment Plan SEQR Hearing (no folder) (Folder 253, Box 6)
    - Poughkeepsie Waterfront ’89-90 De Laval Property (Folder 254, Box 6)
    - Poughkeepsie Waterfront Advisory Committee (Folder 255, Box 6)
    - Rensselaer Project (Folder 256, Box 6)
    - Town and Village of Coxsakie Draft LWRP (Folder 257, Box 6)
    - Town of Lloyd LWRP (Folder 258, Box 6)
    - Town of Lloyd LWRP Maps (Folder 259, Box 6)
    - Town of Schodack and Village of Castleton-on-Hudson LWRP (Folder 260, Box 6)
    - Town of Stony Point LWRP (Folder 261, Box 6)
    - Town of Red Hook LWRP (Folder 262, Box 7)
    - Village of Sleepy Hollow LWRP (Folder 263, Box 7)
    - Yonkers Downtown LWRP (no folder) (Folder 264, Box 7)
  - Subseries 1.8: Hazardous Waste, 1.8; Boxes: 7 - 8 Folders: 265 - 322
    Series contains documents concerning the exposure and disposal of hazardous waste
    - Agricultural Pesticide Use in Estuarine Drainage Areas (Folder 265, Box 7)
    - Annual Hazardous Waste Site Remedial Program EvaluationReports (Folder 266, Box 7)
    - Bioremediation (Folder 267, Box 7)
    - A Compendium of Hazardous Waste Legislation (Folder 268, Box 7)
    - Critical Review of the NYS Hazardous Waste Cleanup Program (Folder 269, Box 7)
    - Draft NYS Inactive Hazardous Waste Remedial Plan (Folder 270, Box 7)
    - Educating Small Quantity Generators (Folder 271, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Materials Emergency Planning Guide (Folder 272, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Substance Study (Folder 273, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste: Data Management Problems Delay EPA’s Assessment of Minimization Efforts (Folder 274, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste: DOD’s Efforts to Improve Management of Generation, Storage and Disposal (Folder 275, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Dump Sites: Dutchess (Folder 276, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Dump Sites: New York State (Folder 277, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Facility Siting: A National Survey June 1987 (Folder 278, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Facility Siting in NYS: The Evolution of a Promising Public Policy (Folder 279, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Incineration: The Cement Kiln Option (Folder 280, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Information: Focus on NYS (Folder 281, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Management System: General July 1985 (Folder 282, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Reduction: Federal Model Pollution Prevention Legislation (Folder 283, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Reduction: Federal Pollution Prevention Act of 1990 (Folder 284, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Reduction: General Information - Newsletters, Articles (Folder 285, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Reduction: New York State DEC Pollution Prevention Unit (Folder 286, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Reduction: Success Stories (New York State) (Folder 287, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Responsible Party Clean Up Efforts Require Improved Oversight (Folder 288, Box 7)
    - Hazardous Waste Treatment Standards Under the Land Disposal Restrictions (Folder 289, Box 7)
    - Household Hazardous Waste Fact Sheets (Folder 290, Box 7)
    - Identification and Listing of Hazardous Wastes Jan 1992 (Folder 291, Box 7)
    - Identification and Listing of Hazardous Wastes July 1985 (Folder 292, Box 7)
    - Inactive Hazardous Waste Disposal Sites in NYS April 1994 (Folder 293, Box 7)
    - Inactive Hazardous Waste Draft Regulations and Regulatory Impact Statement 1991 (Folder 294, Box 7)
    - Industrial Hazardous Waste Management (Folder 295, Box 7)
    - Leadership Handbook on Hazardous Waste (Folder 296, Box 7)